Guide to the Edwards Pierrepont Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Edwards Pierrepont papers
1813-1902
MS 400
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3.25
The papers consist of correspondence correspondence, legal and financial documents, printed matter, and other papers of Edwards Pierrepont, attorney, judge, Attorney General of the United States, and minister to Great Britain. Some of the correspondence relates to such questions as Reconstruction, bimetallism, the "whiskey ring" controversy, the Hayes-Tilden election, and the Republican Party. Important correspondents include William Maxwell Evarts, Adelbert Ames, Hamilton Fish, Ulysses S. Grant, William H. Seward, Edwin M. Stanton, and Roscoe Conkling.
Pierrepont, Edwards, 1817-1892
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased in 1964 and 2003.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series and one addition: I. Correspondence, 1845-1902. II. Special Files, 1813-1902.
Scope and Contents
The Edwards Pierrepont Collection, though quite small, does provide important materials pertaining to various aspects of his professional and personal life. There are also materials relating to the important political issues of the day. The collection is divided into two series: CORRESPONDENCE and SPECIAL FILES. CORRESPONDENCE is divided into two subsections: "General Correspondence" and "Correspondence of Others."
"General Correspondence," which forms the major part of the series, includes letters about legal cases from clients and other lawyers, letters of congratulation on Pierrepont's appointments to various positions and on speeches he gave or pamphlets he wrote, letters from friends and officials in Great Britain, and letters concerning a published letter of advice written by Pierrepont to his son, Edward Pierrepont. In addition, there are letters from Samuel Augustus Willoughby Duffey (1843-1887), Pierrepont's nephew and a presbyterian minister and hymnologist, and from Samuel Augustus Willoughby, Pierrepont's father-in-law, for whom Pierrepont acted as attorney.
Many of the letters Pierrepont received relate to some of the important political issues of the day. There are, for example, a number of letters from William Maxwell Evarts, a classmate and life-long friend of Pierrepont's, who became Secretary of State and Attorney General. These include letters concerning Evarts' Civil War mission to England, the impeachment of President Johnson, the Hayes-Tilden election, and political affairs in general. There are also letters from Roscoe Conkling, mainly of a personal nature, but also touching upon the Republican party.
Pierrepont received a number of letters and telegrams pertaining to the Mississippi crisis, a series of armed uprisings by white vigilanties against the Negro "scalawag" coalition which formed the backbone of Radical Reconstruction in the south. Letters from the following persons are pertinent: Adelbert Ames, governor of Mississippi; Blanche Kelso Bruce; W. W. Dedrick; Hamilton Fish, Secretary of State; President Ulysses S. Grant, and his son, Ulysses S. Grant, Jr. (1852-1929); J. B. Guthrie; Levi P. Luckey, Grant's secretary; W. Noonan, and A. Warner.
Letters pertaining to the "whiskey ring" include those written to Pierrepont by Benjamin Helm Bristow, Secretary of the Treasury; David Patterson Dyer, United States representative, and President Grant. There are also letters written by Pierrepont to David Patterson Dyer, Scott Lord, and President Grant.
Letters on the question of bimetallic currency were written to Pierrepont by J. B. Bick, U. S. Senator; Richard P. Bland; Frederick Augustus Conkling, U. S. Representative; the National Bi-metallic Coinage Association; the National Executive Silver Committee (of which Pierrepont was a member); Henry E. Pierrepont; William E. Rogers; William Sawkerner; and William M. Stewart.
Other correspondents of note include Simeon E. Baldwin, jurist and governor of Connecticut; Henry Barnard, first U. S. commissioner of education; James Birney, lawyer and diplomat; George Bliss, U. S. district attorney for the southern district of New York; Simon Cameron, Secretary of War; Edward C. Cannington, U. S. district attorney for Washington; John Adams Dix, governor of New York and United States minister to France; Timothy Dwight, president of Yale College; Marshall O. Roberts, a leading capitalist; William H. Seward, secretary of state; Benjamin Silliman, Jr., chemist; and Edwin M. Stanton, Secretary of War. There is also a letter and printed circular signed by William Marcy Tweed and others.
"Correspondence of Others" consists of letters received by Pierrepont's wife and a number of business letters received by Alfred H. P. Edwards, whose estate Pierrepont administered. Correspondents of note, not previously mentioned, includes Noah Davis, U. S. district attorney for the southern district of New York; Frederick William Seward, Undersecretary of State; John Palmer Usher, Secretary of the Interior; and Henry Ward Beecher.
SPECIAL FILES consists primarily of legal and financial documents, newspaper clippings, and copies of printed articles. Most of the legal material pertains to cases in which Pierrepont acted as attorney. In addition, there are affidavits, contracts, some of which relate to Pierrepont's private transactions as a property-holder, and papers relating to the estates which Pierrepont administered. The financial material consists mostly of receipts received by Pierrepont and his wife, purchases made in Europe. There are also insurance certificates, promissory notes, and miscellaneous receipts. Of particular interest are two proclamations (1874 and 1875) by President Grant concerning the Mississippi crisis.
A calendar of the important correspondence in the Collection is contained in the Appendix to this Register. Additional important correspondence has been added to the Collection since this calendar was completed.
Biographical / Historical
Edwards Pierrepont, attorney, judge, Attorney General of the United States, and minister to Great Britain, was born in North Haven, Connecticut, the son of Giles and Eunice (Munson) Pierpont (Edwards later adopted an early family spelling of his surname), March 4, 1817. He attended Yale College, graduating in 1837. Pierrepont studied law at the New Haven Law School and was admitted to the bar in 1840. From 1840 to 1841, he was a tutor at Yale. In the latter year he went to Columbus, Ohio, where he became a law partner of Phineas B. Wilcox. In 1846 he moved to New York City and established a successful legal practice. He also became an active worker for the Democratic party and was elected judge of the superior court of New York City in 1857. He was a supporter of the Union cause and helped to organize the War Democrats in support of the reelection of Lincoln in 1864. He returned to the regular Democratic party in the election of 1866, but with the nomination of Seymour and Blair in 1868, he switched his support to Ulysses S. Grant who later appointed him to several offices.
In 1867 Pierrepont assisted the United States Attorney General in the prosecution of John H. Surratt for complicity in the assassination of Lincoln. He was a member of the New York state constitutional convention, 1867-1868, and a member of the Committee of Seventy which exposed and attacked the "Tweed ring." Pierrepont was appointed Attorney General of the United States in 1875. From 1876 to 1877 he served as minister to Great Britain. In the latter part of his life, Pierrepont published many pamphlets on financial questions, most of which advocated the adoption of a bimetallic standard of currency.
Pierrepont was married in 1846 to Margaretta Willoughby of Brooklyn, New York. He died on March 6, 1892. (See also the chronology which follows).
CHRONOLOGY - Pierrepont, Edwards, 1817-1892
1817 Born in North Haven, Connecticut, son of Giles and Eunice (Munson) Pierpont; great-great-grandson of the Reverend James Pierpont, a founder of Yale College; christened Edwards Munson Pierpont
1833 Entered Yale College in the Class of 1837; classmate of William Maxwell Evarts, Benjamin Silliman, Jr., Samuel Jones Tilden, and Morrison Remick Waite.
1837 Graduated from Yale College.
1837-1841 Studied law in Columbus, Ohio and at New Haven Law School; served as a tutor in Yale College, 1840-1841.
1841-1845 Practiced law in Columbus, Ohio.
1846 Removed to New York City and entered the practice of law; married Margaretta Willoughby.
1848 Daughter, Margaretta Willoughby Pierrepont, born.
1857 Elected Judge of the Superior Court of the City of New York (served 1857-1860).
1860 Son, Edward Pierrepont, born.
1862 Appointed to Special Commission on Prisoners of State, together with John Adams Dix.
1864 Instrumental in organizing War-Democrats in favor of Lincoln's re-election.
1867 Elected a member of the New York State Constitutional Convention; appointed by the United States Attorney General to conduct the prosecution against John H. Surratt, accomplice in the assassination of Abraham Lincoln.
1868 Supported Ulysses S. Grant for president.
1869 Appointed United States Attorney for the Southern District of New York (served 1869-1870).
1870 Member of "Committee of Seventy" against "Tweed ring" in New York.
1871 Named director, counsel, and treasurer of the Texas and Pacific Railroad.
1872 Campaigned for Ulysses S. Grant in the Grant-Greeley presidential contest.
1873 Declined nomination as United States Minister to Russia; awarded an honorary Doctor of Laws degree from Yale College.
1875 Appointed United States Attorney General in the Grant Cabinet (served 1875-1876). Involved in prosecution of the "whiskey ring."
1876 Appointed Envoy Extraordinary and Minister Plenipotentiary to Great Britain (served 1876-1877).
1878 Awarded an honorary D.C.L. from Oxford University; re-entered private practice.
1883 Elected director of the Chicago Central Elevated Railroad Company.
1885? Death of son, Edward Pierrepont.
1892 Died March 7 in New York City.
Bimetallism; Law; Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877) -- Mississippi; Whiskey fraud; Europe; United States -- Foreign relations; United States -- History -- 1865-1898; United States -- Politics and government; Diplomats; Lawyers; Ames, Adelbert, 1835-1933; Barnard, Henry, 1811-1900; Beecher, Henry Ward, 1813-1887; Bick, J. B.; Birney, James Gillespie, 1792-1857; Bland, Richard Parks, 1835-1899; Bliss, George, 1830-1897; Bristow, Benjamin Helm, 1832-1896; Bruce, Blanche Kelso, 1841-1898; Cameron, Simon, 1799-1889; Cannington, Edward C.; Conkling, Frederick A. (Frederick Augustus), 1816-1891; Conkling, Roscoe, 1829-1888; Davis, Noah, 1818-1902; Dix, John A. (John Adams), 1798-1879; Dwight, Timothy, 1828-1916; Evarts, William Maxwell, 1818-1901; Fisk, Hamilton, 1808-1893; Grant, Ulysses S. (Ulysses Simpson), 1822-1885; Grant, Ulysses S., 1852-1929; Pierrepont, Edwards, 1817-1892; Pierrepont, Henry Evelyn, 1808-1888; Roberts, Marshall Owen, 1814-1880; Seward, Frederick William, 1830-1915; Seward, William H. (William Henry), 1801-1872; Stanton, Edwin M. (Edwin McMasters), 1814-1869; Usher, John Palmer, 1816-1889; National Bimetallic Coinage Association; National Executive Silver Committee; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); Yale University -- Faculty
- Correspondence, 1845-1902; Series I; 1' 5 1/2" (4 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  CORRESPONDENCE is divided into two subsections: "General Correspondence" and "Correspondence of Others." "General Correspondence" contains letters received by Pierrepont arranged alphabetically by the name of the writer, followed by the letters written by Pierrepont. These are arranged alphabetically by the name of the addressee. Letters within each folder are arranged chronologically.
  "Correspondence of Others" is arranged alphabetically by the name of the person to whom the letter is addressed.
  A calendar providing more detailed information about selected correspondence from boxes 1-3 in this series is available elsewhere in this finding aid.
  - General
    - A, 1864, 1875-1876, 1883, 1886, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ames, Adelbert, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Ba-Bir, 1850, 1869, 1874-1877, 1881, 1885, 1888-1889, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bis-Bos, 1855-1870, 1875-1877, 1885-1886, n.y. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bou-But, 1864-1890, n.y. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Baldwin, Simeon Eben, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Barnard, Henry, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bick, J. B., 1888 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Birney, James, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bland, R. P. (Committee on Coinage, Weights and Measures), 1886 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bliss, George, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bristow, Benjamin Helm, 1873, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bruce, Blanche Kelso (and others), 1875 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Ca-Ci, 1862-1863, 1869, 1875-1877, 1887, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Co-Cr, 1854, 1862-1877, 1886-1889 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Cameron, Simon, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Cannington, Edward C., 186- (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Chicago Central Elevated Railroad Company, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Conkling, Frederick Augustus, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Conkling, Roscoe, 1869-1881, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - D, 1852-1856, 1864-1878, 1886-1889 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Dedrick, W. W., 1875 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Dix, John A., 1867, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Duffield, Samuel Augustus Willoughby (nephew), 1860-1886 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Dwight, Timothy, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Dyer, David P., 1875 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - E, 1854-1857, 1864-1869, 1875-1877, 1881-1887, n.y. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Evarts, William Maxwell, 1852, 1857, 1860-1862, 1864, 1867-1868 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Evarts, William Maxwell, 1869-1870, 1872, 1874-1876 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Evarts, William Maxwell, 1877-1879, 1882, 1886, 1889-1890, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - F, 1852-1853, 1862, 1864, 1869-1887, n.y. (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Fish, Hamilton, 1875, n.y. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - G, 1856-1869, 1874-1886, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Grant, Ulysses Simpson, 1875, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Grant, Ulysses Simpson, Jr., 1876 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Guthrie, J. B., 1875 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - H, 1854-1856, 1863-1869, 1875-1880, 1885-1887, n.y (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - [Henry, James M?], 1875-1876, 1878 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - I, J, K, 1854-1856, 1862-1864, 1870-1877, 1880-1882, 1885, 1889, n.y. (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - L, 1854-1856, 1859, 1863-1864, 1868, 1874-1877, 1883, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Luckey, Levi P., 1875 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - M, 1861-1877, 1885-1886 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - N, 1864, 1868, 1875, 1886, 1889 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - National Bi-metallic Coinage Association, National Executive Silver Committee, 188-, 1888, 1890-1891 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Noonan, W., 1875 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - O, 1875-1877 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - P, 1857, 1862-1875, 1881-1890 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Pierrepont, Henry E., 1885, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - R, 1853, 1856, 1864-1870, 1875-1877, 1883, 1888, 1890, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Roberts, Marshall O., 1851, 1864, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Rogers, William E., 1890 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Sa-Sed, 1857?, 1864-1876, 1881-1884, undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Ses-Si, 1852, 1855, 1864, 1866?, 1874-1877, 1882-1887 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Sm-Sta, 1845, 1848, 1856, 1864, 1866, 1874, 1877, 1885-1886 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Ste-Sw, 1856, 1862-1877, 1882-1886, 1891, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Sawkner, William (First Comptroller's Office), 1885 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Seward, William H., 1862 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Sherman, William Tecumseh, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 57a)
    - Silliman, Benjamin (Jr.), 1877, 1879 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Stanton, Edwin McMasters, 1862-1864 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Stewart, William M., 1890 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Ta-Thom, 1862-1869, 1874-1875, 1890-1891, undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Thor-Tu, 1856-1859, 1863-1864, 1872-1876, 1885, 1889 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Tweed, William Marcy and others, 1864, 1868 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - U, V, 1848, 1853-1856, 1865-1866, 1873-1875, 1880-1885 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Wa-We, 1848, 1864-1870, 1876-1879, 1889 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Wh-Wo, 1848, 1854-1856, 1864-1869, 1873-1877, 1889 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Warner, A., 1875 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Willoughby, S. A. (father-in-law), 1854-1856, 1865-1869, 1869 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Y, Z, 1869, [1876?] (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Unidentified, 1845?, 1849, 1856-1868, 1874-1878, 1885-1890, undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - From Edwards Pierrepont To
    - A-Z, 1850, 1866, 1876-1877, 1880, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Conkling, Roscoe, 1869 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Dyer, D. P., 1875 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Grant, Ulysses Simpson, 1869, 1874-1876 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Lord, Scott (incomplete draft?), 1876 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Of Others
    - A-C, 1845, 1848, 1862-1865, 1873-1879 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Carmick, E. H. from Evarts, William Maxwell, 1880 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - D, 1862, 1876, 1888 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Davis, Noah (copy), 1871 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Dix, John A., 1864 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - E, 1855 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Edwards, Alfred H. P., 1852-1853, 1856 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Evarts, William Maxwell from Seward, Frederick William (enclosing copy of letter from Seward, W. H. to Dimick, Justin), 1862 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Fish, Hamilton from Beecher, Henry Ward; from Schultz, J. S. together with a letter to Grant, U. S. from Beecher, Henry Ward (copies), 1877 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - G-N, 1847-1848, 1862, 1877, undated (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - O-P, 1847, 1873, 1875, 1881, 1888 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Pierrepont, Mrs. Edwards, 1870, 1876-1877, 1885-1886, 1890-1895, 1902, undated (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Roberts, Marshall O., 1855-1866, 1870-1875, 1888, undated (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - S, 1864, 1865 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Seward, Frederick William from Evarts, William Maxwell, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Stanton, Edwin McMasters from Evarts, William Maxwell, 1862 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Stephenson, Maggie from Willoughby, S.A., 1865 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - T, 1848 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Usher, John Palmer (Secretary of the Interior) from Union Pacific Railroad Company (copy), 1863 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - V-W, 1856, 1865, 1883 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Willoughby, S. A., 1856, 1850, 1879 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Unidentified from Seitz, Charles, 1866 (Box 4, Folder 97)
- Special Files, 1813-1902; Series II; 1'(3 boxes)
  SPECIAL FILES is arranged alphabetically by category and alphabetically by the name or title within each category. Items within each folder are arranged chronologically.
  - Affidavits
    - Miscellaneous, 1850, 1863-1865, 1868-1869, 1873 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Pierrepont, Edwards, [1890?] (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Agreements
    - Land purchases and sales - Pierrepont, Edwards, 1844, 1857, 1860, 1865, 1867 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Oversize material (Folder 8)
    - Leases - Pierrepont, Edwards to others, 1846, 1854, 1860, 1866 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, of others, 1828, 1832, 1846-1851, 1867-1872, 1889, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous - Pierrepont, Edwards with others, 1850, 1857-1860, 1871-1872 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Mortgages - Pierrepont, Edwards, 1857 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Oversize material (Folder 8)
    - Railroad companies (printed), 1875, 1886, 1887 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Articles
    - "Commerce - the law of our National Growth"; on Gold Reserves, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Oversize material (Folder 8)
  - Autobiographical note
    - Pierrepont, Edwards - typed copy from "Yale College, a sketch of its history" edited by Kingsley, William L., Vol 1 p. 482, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Cases
    - Allerton, George W. v. Barmore, William Baker, Lucy v. Roberts, Marshall O., 1848, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Bean, Cotton W. v. Edge, George W., 1862-1863 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Belmont, August et al v. Erie Railroad Company et al., 1868 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Bigger, William v. Allair Works, The, 1854 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - [Binfse?] John and Giberton, Adrien v. Alcock, James, 1859 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Boyd, John W. v. Morgan, Francis T. and Oliver, Joseph, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Burdell, Margaret by her next friend v. Burdell, John, 1847-1848 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Case, Albert S. and Phillips, Pierpont, 1848 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - v. (i) O'Keefe, John; Doherty, Patrick and McClosky, Arthur (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - v. (ii) Smith, James M. Jr. and [Tilym?] Joseph P. (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Charlton, Thomas v. Ellis, Robert; Ellis, T. P. and Hogg, John T., 1853-1855 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Denison, Minnie I. et al. v. Dove, John et al, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Downing, George R. V. Kelly, John, 1866 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Dows, John, survivor of [Carry, Ira. B?] v. Perrin, James and Caleb, Madison M., undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Eastman, Smith J. v. O'Connor, Francis B., undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Edwards, Alfred H. P. in the matter of the estate of, 1857 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Edge et Al. v. Robertson, Collector, 1884 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Ellis, Robert; Hunt, Noah S. and Ellis Thomas P. v. Hunt, John D. and Kingsbury, Joseph, 1855 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Florence Sewing Machine Company v. Warford, William R. and Vanderveir, 1869 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Fraschieris, Jose v. Heuriques, David M. and Ferris, Thomas T., 1862 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Goodenough, Rollin A. v. Rarey, John S. Gray, John A. C. v. Bowen, Henry C., 1863 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Griffith, Walter S. and Dunning, Czar - administrators v. Brown, William O., 1848 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Hallgarten, Lazarus v. Lane, Frederick A., 1867 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Hatch, Sarah C. v. Penanet Clara M. and Eugene; and Ensenwein, Frederick, executor, [1867?] (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Hewlett, John S. v. Browne, Robert W., 1857 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Hogg, John T. v. Ellis, Robert and Ellis, Thomas P., 1854 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Hogg, John T. v. Hunt, Noah L. & others, 1859 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Hurd, Elane v. Coughlin, William, 1848 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Kemble, Peter and Warner, Abram B. v. McHenry, James, 1869 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Kendall, Josiah F. v. Hodgins, John, [1858?] (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Lake, Joseph T. and Klemm, Otho v. Bank of Toledo, 1848, 1851 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Lewis, Joseph L., concerning the will of, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Long, Nathaniel R. and Davenport, John v. Ellis, Robert and Ellis, Thomas P., 1856 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Lowry, Joseph L. etal. v. Lester, John H. et al., undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - McClusky, John and Seymour, John, v. Adams, William H., 1848 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Mackey, William, executor of estate of Fayerweather, Ransom v. Brooks, Orville, executor; Trotter, William; Fayerweather, Josiah S.; Falconer, John and Catherine; Blarney, Susannah, and Pierrepont, Margaretta, 1864 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Matthews, Edward v. Chicopee Manufacturing Company, 1866 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Mercantile Library Association, Board of Directors of, and Vulte, Theodore H., in re arbitration between, 1864 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Merchant, William H., in re proving the last will and testament of, 1862-1863 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Michigan, State of v. Phenix Bank of New York, [1857?] (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - New York Belting and Packing Company v. Metropolitan Insurance Company, 1857 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - New York, State of v. Jeremiah, George A., 1865 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Pennsylvania, State of v. Wheeling Bridge Company, 1850 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - The People v. Titus, Charles R., 1880 (Box 6, Folder 41)